anbusiness.com 2009-03-30

# Security and privacy

This is our Privacy Statement. It explains how this site obtains, uses and keeps safe information about you. We’re committed to keeping your personal information safe and confidential both online and offline.

This Privacy Statement is not designed to form a legally binding contract between Abbey and users of our website or online services. It is a guide towards our online protection standards, but of course it is of utmost importance to abide by the principles stated here.

##  Online application 

If you apply for an account online, before you enter any personal details into the online form, we’ll tell you how your information will be used in our data protection statement and in the relevant terms and conditions. You will be asked to confirm that you have read and understood these before your application can proceed.

We might occasionally send you information about accounts and services which we think would be of interest to you. If you’d prefer us not to use your contact details in this way you can opt out by leaving the tick box that is available to you unticked.

## Contacting us

Contacting us by phone

You can call our customer services team on 0845 6070 666. For your convenience, we also operate a call-back service – accessed via www.anbusiness.com. You give your number over the Internet and we’ll call you back on your normal telephone line. These calls are not made across the Internet. We’ll store your details on systems that aren’t connected to the Internet – although to help us improve our service we might record or monitor phone calls.

Contacting us by email

When you email us, we collect some personal details like your name, address and phone numbers. Email isn’t 100% secure - so we advise that you keep personal information to a minimum. With this in mind, don’t transmit account information using email.

Emails are stored on our standard internal contact systems which are secure and can’t be accessed by external parties. We store this information for an indefinite period of time in order to identify trends.

## Using our calculators, decision tools, guides and budget planners 

To use our range of calculators, tools, guides and budget planners, you’ll have to give us details of your financial situation and needs. The information we ask for will depend on what type of product or account you’re interested in.

But please remember: When you use a calculator, guide, decision tool or budget planner all of the details you provide are anonymous – and once you leave we **never** store your details, unless for example, you decide to save a quote.

## Surveys and competitions 

We’ll treat any survey or competition information you provide with the same high standard of care as we do all other customer information, using any details provided strictly within the terms of the competition and this Privacy Statement. 

##  Sharedealing 

Within Abbey Sharedealing you can research information on UK listed companies and AIM shares listed on the London Stock Exchange. You do it anonymously, and we’re not able to identify you as an individual from your research. Please note: our online sharedealing service is provided by Abbey Stockbrokers Limited (“ASL”). ASL is part of the Abbey group of companies.

## Cookies 

We use independent companies to measure and analyse how people use the ‘freely accessible’ areas of the Abbey website. They use cookies to gather and collate information such as the number of pages viewed on the site, the number of visitors and common ways of arriving at or leaving the site. Doing this enables us to keep our content and navigation fresh and useful. 

We don’t and won’t link any information collected by these outside agencies with any personal information collected about you on the website.

What’s in a cookie? 

A cookie is a small file that can be saved onto your computer when you visit a website. We use them to monitor visits to areas of our website. Abbey's site-tracking cookies don’t contain name or address information, but they do contain… 

  * A uniquely generated random number – so that we differentiate one visitor from another. 
  * The date and time of your last visit to the website. 

We use two main types of cookie: 

  * **Permanent cookies** :These are the ones stored on your computer to track repeat visits and where you’ve been on the site. 
  * **Temporary cookies** : These are used to make sure that services like e-banking work properly. When you close your browser down they are deleted from your computer.

Your web browser lets you turn off both permanent and temporary cookies. However, if you do disable cookies you might not be able to use some of the services on this website. 

If you want to turn off cookies on your browser, follow the instructions below and select the ‘disable/reject’ options at the end. 

If you’ve turned off cookies on your browser but want to turn them back on again follow these simple steps specific to your browser version and then choose ‘accept’. 

Microsoft Internet Explorer v5

To enable 'cookies' using Internet Explorer v5:

1) Click on the 'Tools' menu.   
2) Select 'Internet Options'.  
3) Click on the 'Security' tab. and choose the 'Custom Level' button.  
4) Find the 'Cookies' option and enable both types, 'stored...' (Permanent cookies) and 'per session...' (Temporary cookies). 

Microsoft Internet Explorer v6

To enable 'cookies' using Internet Explorer v6:

1) Click on the 'Tools' menu.   
2) Select 'Internet Options'.  
3) Click on the 'Privacy' tab and choose the 'Advanced options' button,  
4) Check the 'Override automatic cookie handling' tick-box.  
5) Enable the 'First party' cookies by choosing the 'Accept' or 'Prompt' option.  
6) Enable the 'Third party' cookies by choosing the 'Accept' or 'Prompt' option. 

Netscape Navigator v4 and above

To enable cookies using Netscape v4 and above: 

1) Click on 'Edit' on the menu bar and select 'Preferences… ',   
2) Choose the 'Advanced' category,   
3) Choose the 'Accept all cookies' option and click OK to confirm.

##  Your information and marketing 

We **will** tell you if we intend to use your information for marketing purposes and we’ll give you the opportunity to opt out if you want to. 

If you receive emails and don't want to in future, please use the email address below to let us remove you from our list. [unsubscribe@abbey.com ](mailto:unsubscribe@abbey.com)

## Correcting mistakes 

You are of course entitled to get hold of information held about you, and if you find it’s inaccurate you can have the information corrected and/or deleted. 

To find out more visit the website of the Information Commissioner at:[ www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk.](http://www.ico.gov.uk/)

##  Contacting us about our Privacy Statement 

If you think this Privacy Statement hasn’t answered all your questions, or you want to know more, please contact our customer services team, who will be more than willing to help you. Their e-mail address is [customer.services@abbey.com](mailto:customer.services@abbey.com)

## Legal information

Links to other websites

Certain hypertext links in this website may lead you to websites which are not under the control of Abbey National Plc. When you activate these, you may leave the Abbey Business website. These links are provided solely for your convenience and do not represent any endorsement or recommendation by Abbey National Plc.

Abbey National Plc accepts no responsibility or liability for the contents of any website to which a hypertext link exists and gives no representation or warranty as to the information on such websites. Abbey National Plc accepts no responsibility or liability for any loss arising from any contract entered into with any website to which a hypertext link exists.

J4B – This site is provided by J4B Plc. The J4B site contains links to external sites and Abbey does not accept responsibility for the content of these other sites.

No liability for unavailability

Abbey National Plc accepts no liability for any loss that may arise if the goods or services advertised within this website become unavailable.

Customer responsibility

It is your responsibility to ensure that your computer is virus protected. Abbey National Plc accepts no responsibility for any loss you may suffer as a result of accessing and downloading information from this site.
